操作界面很简单
The interface is pretty simple.
你把横坐标"X"值输在这里
You put your horizontal "X" coordinate here,
纵坐标"Y"值输入这里
vertical "Y" coordinate here.
等数值让你满意了  就可以按下发射按钮
When you're happy with those, you press this button.
懂了
Got it.
莱纳德  你肯定猜不到我在网上找到了谁
Leonard, you'll never guess who I just found online--
瞄得真准
Nice shot.
都是他大头的功劳
Eh, his giant head did most of the work.
真是"成熟"啊
Very mature.
算你们走运  我现在不玩那种喷彩摩丝了
You're lucky I'm out of Silly String.
我刚才是说  莱纳德
As I was saying, Leonard,
你肯定猜不到我在网上找到了谁
you'll never guess who I just found online:
质子教授
Professor Proton.
开什么玩笑
You're kidding.
-他居然还健在  -没错
- He's still alive? - Yes!
谁是质子教授
Who's Professor Proton?
他是一档超棒节目的主持人...
He was the host of this great--
太棒了
Yes!
抱歉  跟我说说质子教授
Sorry, tell me about Professor Proton.
质子教授是我小时候最爱看的
Professor Proton hosted my favorite science show
一档科学节目的主持人
when I was a child.
我从未落下过一集
I never missed an episode.
他通过利用日常用品来实践科学原理
He demonstrated scientific principles using everyday objects.
超级酷的
It was pretty cool.
你错用"酷"来形容傻事的时候真可爱
Aw, so cute when you use the word "Cool" wrong.
小孩就常把"意大利面"说错成"大意利面"
Like when kids say "pasghetti."
天啊
Oh, dear Lord!
莱纳德  快看
Leonard, look!
还能请他出席聚会或其他场合
He's still available for parties and events.
我们应该请他来
We should hire him.
请他来干嘛
Hire him to do what?
做任何我们想做的事
Well, whatever we want.
一起玩  做实验
Hang out, do experiments,
跟他拍12张不同的照片
make him take 12 pictures with us
然后做成日历
so we can make a calendar.
能跟他一起玩一定超级棒
It would be pretty awesome to hang out with him.
我也错用"超级棒"这词了  对吗
I just used "awesome" wrong, didn't I?
我现在就发邮件给他
Well, I'm E-mailing him right now.
你还记得他节目的主题曲吗
Do you remember his old theme song?
当然记得
Of course I do.
* 拿起你的护目镜  穿上你的实验袍 *
* Grab your goggles, put your lab coat on *
* 质子教授  大驾光临 *
* Here he comes, Professor Proton.*
生活大爆炸 第六季  第二十二集
我刚发现我这周末
Hey, I just found out I have to be at
都得待在望远镜实验室
the telescope lab all weekend.
你和伯纳黛特能照顾下我的狗狗吗
Any chance you and Bernadette could take care of my dog?
你何不直接把她关进狗笼里
Why don't you put her in a kennel?
你何不把你妈送去养老院
Why don't you put your mother in a home?
老实说  她更适合关笼子里
To be honest, she'd do better in the kennel.
我会跟妮妮说  应该没问题
I'll talk to Bernie. I'm sure it's fine.
谢谢你
Thank you.
美梦成真了  美梦成真了
It's happening! It's happening!
质子教授要来我们家了
Professor Proton is coming to our house.
真的假的
You're kidding!
你是说那个主持白痴儿童节目的人吗
You mean the guy who used to host that lame kids show?
就凭你这句话  你被拒之门外了
And you just got yourself uninvited.
瞧  我就说我能巧妙地踢开他
See? I told you I'd find a tactful way to do that.
你怎么能让他去你家
How'd you get him to come to your house?
质子教授曾经说过
As Professor Proton always says,
"世上无难事
"There is no problem you can't solve
-只怕有脑人"  -他花钱请的
- if you use your noggin." - And he wrote him a check.
对  没错  花大钱哟
Yeah, that, too. Big check.
霍华德叔叔
Uncle Howard!
小肉桂来你家过夜啦
Cinnamon's here for her sleepover party!
你知道如果你中风倒下  她会把你吃掉  对吧
You know if you had a stroke, she'd eat you, right?
我很乐意成为她的美食
And it would be my pleasure to be her num-num.
好吧  我该怎么照顾她
Okay, so what do I need to know to take care of her?
很简单
It's very simple.
早餐她要吃蛋白菜肉馅煎饼
For breakfast, she has an egg-white frittata.
可以给她吃自制薯条
Feel free to give her a choice
或是英式松饼  但不能两样都给她吃
of home fries or an English muffin, but not both.
我们在一起控制体重嘛
We're watching our weight.
正餐的话  可以随便吃点
Uh, for dinner, something simple--
一份小牛排  几个虾  随便什么都行
a veal chop, some scampi, whatever you like.
-真高贵的狗狗  -没错
- Classy dog. - Yes.
对了  别忘了关厕所门
Also, don't forget to close the toilet
不让她会把马桶的水喝光的
or she'll drink out of it.
我深感同情
I feel for ya.
因为我也有一个疯子老妈
I've got a psychotic mommy, too.
莱纳德  你睡觉了吗
Leonard, are you in bed?
-睡了  -我也是
- Yes. - Me, too.
很好
Great.
我睡不着
I can't sleep.
我睡得着  麻烦别吵我
Well, I can, so shut up.
你知道还有不到九个小时
Do you realize that in less than nine hours,
亚瑟·杰弗里斯  也就是质子教授
Arthur Jeffries, a.k.a. Professor Proton,
将会大驾光临我们的公寓吗
will be in our apartment?
谢尔顿  你知道如果你整夜不睡觉
Sheldon, you know that if you stay up all night,
你明天就会犯困
you're gonna be sleepy tomorrow.
犯困的谢尔顿就会变狂躁古怪
And a sleepy Sheldon is a cranky Sheldon.
而狂躁古怪的谢尔顿
And a cranky Sheldon...
其实跟平时的谢尔顿也没什么区别
is actually no different than a regular Sheldon.
晚安
Good night!
我在考虑明天穿燕尾服
I'm thinking of wearing a tuxedo.
那一点也不可笑  晚安
That's not ridiculous. Good night.
你有袖扣吗
Do you have cufflinks?
-没有  -无所谓了
- No. - Ah, just as well.
反正凌晨3点也借不到燕尾服
Where can you rent a tuxedo 3:00 in the morning?
好吧  晚安
Okay, good night.
很高兴见到您  质子教授
Nice to meet you, Professor Proton.
很高兴见到您  质子...
Nice to meet you, Prof...
莱纳德
Leonard?
又干嘛
What?
我还是睡不着
I still can't sleep.
今天在公园真是把这小家伙累坏了
She really tuckered herself out at the park, huh?
是啊  你们俩一起玩的时候真可爱
Yeah, you two were so cute playing together.
玩扔球游戏时
It was kind of fun throwing a ball
没人笑我的感觉真好
and not having anyone laugh at me.
你真贴心  没把球扔太远
And you were sweet not to throw it too far
是怕她的小短腿捣腾坏了吧
so she didn't wear out her tiny legs.
是啊  我扔得近完全是出于担心
Yeah, that's what I was doing.
今天有些时候
You know, there were a few moments today
我几乎觉得我们就是个小家庭
when I almost felt like we were a little family.
-真的吗  -真的
- Really? - Yeah.
我从来没想过要当一位母亲
I never thought of myself as a mom,
但当今天我们仨在外面一起玩时
but when the three of us were out there having fun,
我觉得或许某天我们真的可以建立个小家庭
I felt like maybe someday we could do it.
我们当然可以
Of course we can.
尤其是如果我们的宝宝也这么乖这么安静
Especially if our baby's as calm and quiet
就像这位小公主一样...
as little Cinna...
我勒个去  她不见了
Son of a bitch, she's gone!
她去哪里了
Where'd she go?!
我怎么知道  她又没有留个条
I don't know! She didn't leave a note!
不是你负责
You were the one who was supposed
把她放进婴儿车的吗
to put her back in the stroller!
才不是我  是你啊
No, I wasn't! You were!
-不是我  -就是你
- No, I wasn't! - Yes, you were!
好吧  你个弱鸡扔球像个娘们
Yeah, well, you throw like a girl!
我开始担心了
I'm getting worried.
别紧张  谢尔顿  他就晚到几分钟而已
Relax, Sheldon, he's only a few minutes late.
质子教授上电视时  从来不会迟到
Professor Proton was never late when he was on TV.
每天准时4点打开电视都能看见他
You know, every day, 4:00, he was there.
除非龙卷风在东德克萨斯肆虐
Unless tornadoes were ripping apart East Texas,
这样的话  我们只能边看他边看新闻插播
in which case, we'd join him in progress.
是他打来的
It's him.
您好
Hello.
我明白
Well, I see.
好的
Yes.
没问题  我们可以去接您
All right, we can come get you.
好的  一会见
Yeah, well, see you soon.
-再见  -他在那里
- Bye. - Where is he?
三楼平台那
The third floor landing.
那可怜的老头爬楼梯爬了半个小时
The poor old guy's been walking up the stairs for half an hour.
真的是你
It's really you.
杰弗里斯先生  真的很抱歉
Mr. Jeffries, I am so sorry.
我们应该提前告诉你电梯坏了
We should've told you about the broken elevator.
我同意
I agree.
质子教授  很荣幸见到你
Professor Proton, it's an honor to meet you.
叫我亚瑟就行
Just-just call me Arthur.
莱纳德
Leonard...
你听见了吗
...you hear that?
质子教授让我直呼他名字
Professor Proton said I should call him Arthur.
这意味着我们是朋友了
That means we're friends.
不是
No.
是朋友就会先告诉我电梯坏了
A friend would've-would've told me about the elevator.
快看我
Look at me.
我想离你多近就多近
I can get as close to you as I want
妈妈再也不用担心我的眼睛会坏掉
without my mom saying it's going to ruin my eyes.
他是不是个危险人物
Is, uh, is he dangerous?
其实他是个天才人物
Actually, he's a genius.
真的哦
I am.
你没有正面回答我的问题
Th-That doesn't answer my question.
杰弗里斯先生  我是莱纳德
Mr. Jeffries, I'm-I'm Leonard.
这位是我的女朋友  佩妮
This is my girlfriend, Penny.
-您好  -你好呀
- Hi. - Hello.
希望我没让
Well, I hope I haven't kept
楼上的孩子们等太久
the kids waiting too long for-for the show.
不  楼上没有孩子
Oh, no, there are no kids.
我是你唯一的观众
No, the-the show's for me.
走吧  比比看谁先上去
Come on. I'll race ya...
亚瑟
Arthur.
这位金发女郎真的是你的女朋友吗
Is the, is the blonde girl really your-your girlfriend?
是的  先生
Yes, sir.
你才是天才
You're the genius.
您经常出席像这样的场合吗
So, do you do a lot of appearances like this?
不好说
It-It's hard to say.
我至今还在琢磨
I'm-I'm still trying to figure out what...
你们到底请我来干嘛
what-what this is.
我们只是想跟你一起玩
We just wanted to hang out with you
或许了解下你的人生
and maybe learn a little about your life.
其实没什么好说的
Well, there-there really isn't too much to tell.
自从电视节目取消后
After the TV show was-was canceled,
科学界没有人
nobody in the scientific world
把我当真正的科学家
would, uh, would take me seriously.
所以为了维持生计
So I was forced to do these,
我只好出席一些儿童聚会
uh, children's parties to-to make a living.
真是太糟糕了
That's too bad.
但跟孩子们一起  肯定也有收获吧
But still, working with kids-- it must be rewarding.
常会被小孩咬
You-you get bit a lot.
看看我是否理解了
Let me see if-if I have this straight.
你们俩是物理学家
You-you two are-are physicists,
而你们请我来
and-and you, and you want me
是想让我表演一个儿童科学节目
to do a children's... science show?
是的
Yes.
如果有多余的时间
And if there's time,
麻烦跟我们拍12张不同季节不同着装的照片
take 12 pictures with us in seasonal clothing.
我是个真正的科学家呢
You know, I'm a real scientist.
我是康乃尔大学的博士
I-I have a PhD from Cornell University.
那很棒啊
Yeah, that's great.
你有带你的玩偶来吗
Did you bring your puppet?
没有
No, no.
我讨厌那个玩偶
I-I hate that puppet.
不会吧
Oh, no.
怎么会有人讨厌
How could anybody hate
中微子基诺呢
Gino the Neutrino?
很棒吧
It's nice, huh?
我在易趣上买的  20块
I got him for 20 bucks on eBay.
还包邮哦  亲
Including a-shipping!
这不是梦  对吗
I'm... I'm awake, right?
这一切都真实在发生
Th-This is happening?
小肉桂
Cinnamon!
她没有回应可能是因为
You know, maybe she doesn't recognize her name
我们没用拉杰的口音
because of Raj's accent.
这想法靠谱
Good thinking.
小肉桂  到爸爸碗里来
Cinnamon, come to Daddy!
小肉桂
Cinnamon!
我的小羊排  你在哪呢
Where are you, my little lamb chop?
-惟妙惟肖啊  -谢谢
- Nice. - Thanks.
这事完了以后  别把那嗓音忘了
When this all blows over, remember that voice.
挺让我性趣盎然的
It's kind of a turn-on.
我学拉杰说话会让你兴奋吗
It turns you on when I sound like Raj?
小肉桂
Cinnamon!
我把鸡蛋放在上面
Okay, as-as I put the egg on top,
等火焰熄灭
and-and the flame goes out
烧瓶里的气压减小
and-and the air pressure decreases in-in the flask,
你们认为会发生什么
what do you think will happen?
我好像知道
I think I know.
鸡蛋会被吸进去
It's gonna get sucked in.
它会被吸进去
It's going to get sucked in.
好吧  我不知道
Okay, I didn't know.
答对了
Yes!
瞧  我不是他们那种科学家
See, I'm not a scientist like them.
我发现了
I-I figured that out.
利用原电池原理  让土豆发电
土豆钟  做土豆钟的实验吧
Uh, potato clock. Do potato clock.
那是什么
What's that?
用土豆给钟充电
I-I power a clock with a, with a potato.
不可能吧
Shut up!
还能这样啊
You can do that?
我是说
I mean...
这样不就能解决世界能源危机了吗
wouldn't that solve the world's energy crisis?
还真不能
No.
伙计们
Look, guys,
留着你们的钱  我觉得
keep your money. I-I think, uh...
我觉得我该走了
I-I think I'm done.
怎么了
What-what's wrong?
是她惹你生气了吗
Is she upsetting you?
我可以让她走的
Because I can make her go away.
我是看在她的面子上才待这么久的
No, sh-she's the only reason I've-I've stayed this long.
那是为什么
Then what is it?
我也不知道
I don't know.
我觉得我只是
I think I'm just...
只是不想
I-I just, I just don't want to be
再当质子教授了
Professor Proton anymore.
你怎么能说这种话
Well, how can you say that?
质子教授最棒了
Professor Proton's the best.
我可不这么想
What-what has it ever gotten me?
我都是83岁的老头了
I mean, I'm-I'm an 83-year-old man who has...
箱子里还放着土豆
potatoes in-in his suitcase.
其他科学家把我视为笑柄
Other scientists think-think I'm a joke.
还有
And the...
负责操控基诺的木偶师
the puppeteer who did, who did Gino...
他也...
well, he also...
"操"控了我老婆
did my wife.
杰弗里斯先生
Mr. Jeffries,
我得给你看点东西
I need to show you something.
对于你的痛苦  我很遗憾
I'm sorry to hear about your troubles.
谢谢
Uh, thanks.
如果你不介意的话
But if you don't mind me asking,
我想问问土豆钟是怎么运作的
the potato clock, how does it work?
是钟有猫腻  还是土豆有猫腻
Is it a trick clock or a trick potato?
你们俩平时都交流些啥
Wh-What do you two talk about?
我小时候在德克萨斯给你写过一封信
I wrote a fan letter to you when I was a child in Texas,
你送了我这个有你亲笔签名的照片
and you sent this autographed picture back to me.
还记得吗
Do you remember that?
我给你个提示吧
I'll-I'll give you a hint:
我平时戴着写着自己的地址的手链[老人痴呆]
I have a bracelet with my own address on it.
总之
Well, anyway, um,
你可能觉得难以置信
you may find this hard to believe,
但其实我从小到大没什么朋友
but I didn't have any friends growing up.
这我完全理解
No, I-I get that.
但是  我有你
But, um, I did have you.
每天下午四点钟
And every day at 4:00,
我在家看你在68频道的节目
you'd come to my house on Channel 68,
我们都一起玩科学游戏
and we'd do science together.
要不是你的话
If it hadn't been for you,
谁知道我现在会变成什么样
well, who knows what would've become of me?
我可能当不成世界一流的物理学家
You know? Instead of a world-class physicist,
而成为流浪汉
I could've wound up as a-a hobo.
或者外科医生
Or a surgeon.
我相信世上每天都有许多重要的科学发现
I bet there are important discoveries being made every day
这都归功于你启发了无数的孩子去追求科学
because you inspired millions of kids to pursue science.
从某种角度来说  他们的发现就是你的发现
In a way, their discoveries are your discoveries.
是真的
Yeah, it's true.
整整一代年轻的科学家
A generation of young scientists
都是靠你启发才有了今天
are standing on your shoulders.
谢谢你们
Well, thank-thank you, guys.
这番话对我意义非凡
That... that-that means a lot.
你要知道你在我们心目中的份量  这很重要
Well, it's important you know how much you mean to us.
亚瑟  你还好吗
Arthur, are you okay?
我的
I'm having a...
心脏起搏器出了点问题
problem with my pacemaker.
我去叫救护车
I'll-I'll call for help.
用土豆来充电可以吗
Any chance we could plug it into the potato?
不行
No.
你好
Hello?
什么叫你找到我的狗了
What do you mean, you found my dog?
她在我朋友那儿呢
She's with my friends.
她还好吗
Is she okay?
谢谢你
Oh, thank you.
把你的地址发给我  我这就来
Uh, just text me your address; I'm on my way.
如果她饿了的话  就给她喂点吃的
Oh, and if she's hungry, go ahead and feed her.
但别给她带淀粉的食物
But do not give her anything starchy.
它晚餐要吃意式调味饭
She's having risotto for dinner.
你的生命指数很稳定
Your vitals are stable,
但还是去医院做些检查  以防万一
but let's take you in for some tests just to be safe.
需要我们中的谁陪你坐救护车吗
You want one of us to go with you in the ambulance?
我去
I'll do it!
他不是亲属  不能让他陪同  对吧
He's not a relative, he's not allowed, right?
没这样的规矩  他可以去
No, that's not a rule. He can go.
太好了
Oh, yeah!
今天我连喘口气的机会都没有
I can't catch a break today.
我们收拾好你的东西  就去医院看你
We'll pack up your stuff and meet you at the hospital.
很抱歉事情发展成这样
I'm sorry things turned out this way.
到了这个地步  我只能
Well, at-at this point, I'm just...
庆幸下楼时有人来抬我走
glad someone's carrying me down the stairs.
不仅见到我儿时的英雄
Met my childhood hero,
还能和他一起坐救护车
now I get to ride in an ambulance.
如果能再让他拍挂历照片
Boy, if we can get him to do that calendar,
这将是我人生中最美好的一天
this'll be the best day ever.
真不敢相信把她弄丢了
Can't believe we lost her.
我想什么呢
What was I thinking?
我会是个糟糕的母亲
I'd be a terrible mom.
或许第一个孩子时  你做得不够好
Well, maybe with the first one.
但孩子就跟煎薄饼一样
But kids are like pancakes.
第一个总是要扔掉的废品
The first one's always a throwaway.
-怎么样  -挺好的
- How's this look? - It's fine.
你哪弄来的她的照片
Where'd you get that picture of her?
这不是她
It's not her.
我只是谷歌了一下"被当亲生娃的狗"
I just Googled "Foo-foo little dogs."
是拉杰  别出声
It's Raj. Stay quiet.
真不凑巧
Bad timing.
伯纳黛特刚刚带小肉桂出门溜达了
Bernadette just took Cinnamon out for a walk.
有意思
Interesting.
他们溜到谎言巷了吗
Did they take a walk down Liars' Lane?
什么
What?
说谎者出入的小巷
A lane frequented by liars.
比如说你  你这个大骗子
Like you, you big liar!
她居然在你那里
You have her?
谢天谢地她没事
Oh, thank God she's okay.
我相信你  你却让我失望了
Well, I trusted you, and you let me down.
可怜的小家伙抖了几小时了
The poor thing's been shaking for hours.
真是对不起
I'm really sorry.
等等  你已经找到它几小时了吗
Hang on, you've had her for hours?
对  我去接了它
Yes. I picked her up,
两人一起去做了个按摩  放松下来
and then we both went for massages to try and calm down.
然后去粉红桨果店吃了酸奶
And then we got Pinkberry.
你知道她没事
So you knew she was okay,
就不会接我们电话告诉我们吗
and you couldn't pick up the phone to tell us?
那个  我想...
Well, I-I thought about...
少跟我说废话  先生
Don't "well" me, mister!
我们快担心死了
We've been worried sick!
我们都觉得她已经不在人世了
She could have been dead for all we knew!
你应该觉得羞愧
You should be ashamed of yourself!
对不起  我只是
Sorry. I-I just...
道歉有什么用
Sorry's not good enough!
也许你应该花些时间
Maybe you need to take some time
好好反省下你的所作所为
and think about what you've done!
这招"良心不安"真高
Nice guilt trip.
你会是一个非常出色的妈妈
You are gonna be an amazing mom.
* 软软猫  暖暖猫 *
* Soft kitty, warm kitty, *
* 小小毛绒球 *
* little ball of fur. *
* 快乐猫  瞌睡猫 *
* Happy kitty, sleepy kitty, *
* 呼噜呼噜呼噜 *
* purr, purr, purr. *
谢谢你  谢尔顿
Thank you, Sheldon.
唱得真好听
That-that was very nice.
-要我再唱一遍吗  -不用了
- Want me to sing it again? - No.
唱了四遍  四角俱全  很吉利了
The fourth, the fourth time was-was the charm.
需要我帮你拿点什么吗
There anything I can get for you?
苹果汁
Some apple juice?
果冻
Uh, some Jell-O?
不用了  多谢
No. No, thank you.
但我的确
But I-I do...
需要你帮个忙
I do have a favor to-to ask.
尽管说
Name it.
我明天有场表演
Well, I'm-I'm booked to do
要去参加一个儿童聚会
a children's party tomorrow,
说实话  我觉得我去不了
and, um, frankly I, you know, I-I don't feel up to it.
你肯定去不了
Oh, you're not.
你的样子糟糕极了
You look awful.
谢谢
Th-Thank you.
总之
Anyway, uh...
你比任何人都熟悉我的表演
I mean, you know my act better than... anybody.
我希望
I was, I was hoping
也许
that maybe, you know,
你可以替我去
maybe you'd fill in for me.
你是说
Wha... Are you saying
你要我当质子教授吗
that you want me to be Professor Proton?
对
Yeah.
天啊
Oh, my.
我太荣幸了
What an honor.
这就像是被邀请攀上奥林匹斯圣山
Oh, this is like being asked to ascend Mount Olympus
和众神同桌吃饭
and dine with the gods.
或与阿罕布拉市的一个韩国家庭同桌吃饭
Or a... Korean family in Alhambra.
但他们会知道我不是你
But they'll know I'm not you.
我是不是应该叫自己
Should I call myself...
小质子教授呢
Professor Proton, Jr.?
听起来挺好的
Sounds great.
那么  某种程度上
So, in a way...
感觉就像我是你的儿子
it's like I'm your son.
好...好吧
What-Whatever.
父亲
Father.
随便吧  爱咋地咋地
Sure, what the hell?